# FRONT END SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

yuliia.dobrova@gmail.com 🔀 +1(778)-325-3487 🦿 Vancouver, BC, Canada •

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

As a Front-End Software Developer with over 5 years of experience, I have worked on solo projects, web applications, and ambitious team projects. My solid background in Civil Design-Engineering allows me to bring a unique blend of technical and administrative skills to any project.

With an ability to manage multiple projects meeting tight deadlines, and a creative approach to problem-solving I am dedicated to delivering exceptional results and ensuring the highest level of customer satisfaction.

## **SKILLS**

- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- REST API
- React
- Redux Toolkit
- Axios
- WebSocket
- Flexbox, Grid
- Parcel, Webpack
- Preprocessor SASS (SCSS)
- Material-UI
- Bootstrap, jQuery
- Styled-components
- Node.js
- Express.js
- MongoDB
- NoSQL
- Postman
- Swagger
- JWT (JSON Web token)
- Git
- GitHub
- Vercel, Netlify, Heroku
- Visual Studio Code
- Copilot
- NPM, Yarn
- Responsive/Adaptive design
- Agile, Scrum
- UI / UX Design Principles
- Figma
- Slack
- PM Tools (Click-Up, Jira)
- AutoCAD

## WEBSITE, PORTFOLIO AND PROFILES

https://yuliiadobrova.com/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/yuliia-dobrova/

https://github.com/YuliaDobrova

### **EXPERIENCE**

Front End Software Developer at Research and Production Enterprise "Ukrradioprom" LLC (April 2023 - January 2024)

 Developed a user-friendly web application to efficiently handle clients product database, which resulted in a significant 20% increase in online sales within a period of 6 months.

Front End Software Developer at Web Tech Company "TensionX" ("SaaS Insiders") (February 2022 - March 2023)

- Contributed to collaborative Git practices with a team of 7 developers and successfully delivered an international social media platform for elder women within a 3-month deadline.
- Developed authorization forms, managed backend data exchange, and implemented real-time comment display using WebSocket technology, leading to a 60% decrease in data processing time.
- Integrated text translation for the entire application and enhanced overall user experience, resulting in a 45% increase in international user engagement.
- Improved user experience and system efficiency in an existing School Management System application, digitizing all paperwork related to student marks and success, and introducing specialized analytics interfaces for both parents and teachers, resulting in an 80% increase in the accessibility of student performance data.

Front End Software Developer at Dental Center of Dr. Krolyk (November 2021 - January 2022)

• Created a website design from scratch and developed it in 2 months (interactivity, reviews, geolocation, multilingualism, adapted to different devices, deployed to hosting).

Civil Design Engineer / Head of the Project Department / Front End Software Developer Engineering Company "Avtomagistral" LCC (September 2018 - February 2021)

- As a licensed Civil Design Engineer proficient in AutoCAD, successfully coordinated 50 projects for new design or reconstruction across various infrastructure sectors within 6 months, meeting strict deadlines, while leading a diverse team of 30 engineers and implementing agile PM methodologies.
- Implemented a multi-page business card website for our company with the aim of attracting new customers, leading to a 25% growth in our customer base within 3 months.

#### **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Developer Course (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Node.js) GoIT - International Ed-Tech Company (2021)

**Bachelor's Degree in Water Resources Engineering (AutoCAD)** The Faculty of Geography, National University of Kyiv, Ukraine (2009)

## **LANGUAGES**

• English (fluent)

Ukrainian (fluent)Russian (fluent)